I'm going to explain one of the most
common mistakes that people fall into
when it
comes to selling online.
And some people are even years into social
media, and they
don't understand this fully.
The first thing we need to understand
is that only a
small percentage of our audience want to
do business with us, conservatively, let's
say 1% to 3%. I know
that can seem depressing, but
if you grow your audience to a
decent size, it's enough. Trust me.
And any of you that have followed me for a
while will know that I have a
four-stage, four S's system
that I utilize to get sales.
And I'm going to run through it really
quickly.
And that four-stage system
is social media, squeeze, sell, scale.
And you'll notice
that I have sell down here,
yet a lot of people try
and sell on social media,
and I think that's a big problem.
For us to understand this,
we first must understand how an algorithm
works on
social media. And very simply,
it's not an algorithm
that you're trying to impress,
it's humans.
And every social media algorithm
is going to look at how humans react
to your content.
Asking people to save the video isn't
going to score as well as
hundreds and thousands of people watching
it for a very long period of time,
interacting with it,
and sending it to their friends.
A side tangent is so many people try
and game the system, like, "Share this
workout," "Save this post."
And ultimately,
I just think it makes you look pretty
fucking beggy. So this
is being incredibly conservative.
Let's say the red person here
is the person who's interested in buying
your
products.
They're an ideal target customer.
If you try and sell to them on social
media, and maybe it's a reel that you're
doing saying something like, "Hey, guys,
enrollment is now open for my 12-week
challenge.
So if you're looking to lose fat,
build muscle, or just keep a..." You
get the idea. Let's say you do
that to social media.
Although this person
is potentially interested,
all these people are going to
think to themselves, "Don't care,
mate." And that's not because you've done
a bad
job on social media. It's because
if you do social media right,
you're not there to
sell your product,
you're there to solve problems.
Even this video right now,
I'm here to solve the problem
that people have trying to
sell on social media.
We actually want the majority of our
audience to not be
buyers, which can sound really stupid.
This, to me, is a perfect audience.
If anything, this is far too kind.
This many people are not interested in
buying my
stuff, and only one person that is.
We actually need to create content with
all of these people in mind because if we
go to try and appease
or sell to this person,
all these people are going to signal
to the algorithm
that they're not interested,
and instead it's going to get shown
to no one. So instead,
if we go back to the four S's,
when it comes to social
media, let's not sell. Let's do
that further down the line.
Let's use social media for what it's
really good for.
Let's make content
that all of these people love.
Because if they do,
the algorithm's going to go, "Hey,
we just showed this to this
many people, and they loved it.
So let's show it to a wider audience of
people."
And in that wider audience,
we're probably going to find more people
that are right
for our product or service
that we're selling.
So when we're in
that first stage of socials,
let's not try and sell to people.
Instead, let's try and make content
that people can resonate with, even
if they're
not right for our business model. It
is only by appealing to a mass audience,
it's
only by appealing to the majority of
people that watch your content
that you can go
far and wide enough to find other people
that could be right for you.
This is why every time you try
and promote an offer on your social media,
it falls
flat on its face. Because ultimately,
the majority of people just aren't
interested. And that doesn't mean
that you're doing something wrong.
So the next stage you need to look at
is the squeeze.
We need to come up with something
that all of these people would be
interested in,
and we even want to appease the people
that are never going to buy our stuff.
Let's say this is Dave,
and Dave says to me, "Mate,
I am never going to buy your
business mentorship." I actually want to
be in Dave's good books because he might
know people that are right, or better yet,
if he's a happy person watching
content,
he might have an average view duration of
all my videos of 90%.
And what does that mean?
That because of Dave's behaviors, YouTube,
Instagram, or
TikTok, or whatever,
are going to find more Daves,
and within the more Daves, there
could be someone who
is actually right for this.
So we need to look at this
and think to ourselves, "Okay, what
is it that all of
these people could be interested in?"
And this is where you create a lead magnet
that benefits everyone. This
is where we want to squeeze people.
We want to squeeze the information from
them.
Now, again,
you could fall into the trap of trying to
make this too specific, but
ultimately, once you've got their data,
things can change.
So for instance, the reason
that I got three number one bestselling
books was
because I had a big email list.
When I told Harper Collins
that I had 300,000
people on my email list, they're like,
"Let's write a book." And you've probably
heard of Nutonic before.
We've just done over a million US dollars
in revenue for
the second month in a row,
a lot of which have come from emailing
people.
And the origin of where I got the email
from was probably my PT business or
probably even a book. So the reason
that I say to, again,
get all of these people's
data is you're probably going to even find
some people that aren't right for what
you're selling now
but could be right for what you're selling
in a few years.
I like to remind people that in 2016,
if you told me in 2017
I'd have one of the world's largest online
coaching businesses, I wouldn't have
believed you.
If you'd said in 2019 I'd be getting a
book deal from Harper Collins,
I wouldn't have believed you.
If you told me that in 2021 I
was going to hit a
million followers on social media,
I wouldn't have believed you.
It's only looking back
that things make sense.
And for some of you here watching this,
you might have gone, "Oh, yeah, it always
seemed like James
was going to potentially do this." Well,
it didn't to me.
So again,
we've grown this audience of people
that don't care, people that might,
and people that might in the future.
We want to now almost chuck a net on these
people and try and capture them.
That's where the squeeze comes in.
So you create something called a lead
magnet.
Now, the lead magnets online,
you see me using ManyChat on social media,
or the link's in the description below.
And it's through making videos quite
generic to larger audiences with the
majority
of people that don't want to do business
with me, I can get people onto my lead
magnets.
To me then Selling must occur on email.
One of the benefits I told you about
was last week I was pretty ill.
Even had to push back a webinar because of
how ill I was.
But I churned out emails every single day.
And this month, December,
after Black Friday,
you usually anticipate that your
revenue's going to crash through the
floor.
And we had probably like our fourth
or fifth biggest month ever.
And it was because I wrote about 12 emails
out, and you all have got the
automations coming through.
And the thing is,
when you make the emails good enough,
they might be funny, informative,
storytelling.
Any of you that have signed up to my big
email list will even know the origin as to
why I shaved my head.
And those of you that just heard that
and don't get my emails
have probably just got a little bit of
FOMO, thinking, "Oh, maybe I should be on
his email list so I could find out."
And it's only when you email people.
Sometimes they'll read emails for weeks,
months, sometimes even years, and they
turn into people
that actually want your stuff.
God, this pen has had better days,
hasn't it?
I'll even explain to you in action where
this really benefited me
recently. Let's start with socials.
We don't need to talk about scale
that much in today's video.
So I'm doing a webinar on the 4th of
January.
If you want to come to that,
there's going to be a link in the
description.
And what I just did there
was I used socials to give you a squeeze,
and out of that
we'll probably get some of you signing up
to that webinar.
But about two weeks ago,
I went out on social media with organic
and paid.
And I'm not going to lie to you,
we spent about $9,000 on ads, and we got
5,000 email addresses. Out of those 5,000,
just over 1,000 people turned up for the
webinar. In retrospect,
a lot of people watched it at another time
that could be
convenient to them. And on the day,
did the webinar up here.
It was just over two hours.
I gave people an offer,
and we did $24,000 in business,
which is quite healthy. What? Four,
nearly five return on investment, which is
nice, but the main play
was how we turned it into a squeeze.
So on the day, we had that.
But what we did was we took the rest of
those
people and put them into an email
automation.
We then gave them an offer, and
that month was 380K.
So just getting the emails
and sending the offer alone
was enough to make that
investment worth it. But
when you put them into a squeeze,
put them through some
email automations,
that offer took over 20 days to convert.
If I had just tried to do all of this up
here on socials and I just
sold to them in a webinar
or a live stream,
I wouldn't have been able to re-engage
them and get them to buy. Now,
from the stream, from the emails.
From the stream, from the emails.
Now one of the biggest key factors to all
of this
making sense is when people
are ready to buy. So for instance,
it's 10:38 a.m.
I'm about to walk from here to jujitsu.
If I see your offer for something, even
if I want it, I'm on my way to jujitsu.
I'm on my phone.
I also am from an age demographic where I
don't buy things on my
phone. If I need to book flights,
get my laptop out.
If I need to pay invoices,
I get my laptop out.
If I need to do anything,
In fact,
I've only ever bought one thing in my life
from Instagram, and it was
that thing there.
I don't know why I saw it on an ad,
and I thought it looked kind
of cool. And because my dials
are yellow as well, I thought,
"I'm going to get
that." And now when my son gets in,
my one-and-a-half-year-old son,
he loves just
twisting that knob. And to me, it
was worth it because of that.
That's the only thing I've ever bought
from Instagram, and it was like 10, 15
pound. So even right now, this video
that you're watching, we're in the socials
component.
Let's say we get 5,000 views on this
video. Maybe we get 500 emails.
Maybe 10 sales. 20 grand of business.
But then out of those emails,
I might start selling you other things.
But ultimately, all the time
that I've got in front of you on YouTube,
on social
media, I'm not going to sell to you,
I'm going to solve to you.
I'm going to solve your problems.
It's the best use of time
that I could ever use
in these few minutes
that you've just given me.
And out of all those opportunities to try
and get something from you, I'm not
asking for your money.
I'm just asking for your email address.
That to me could be wrong,
but it's got 130,000 people into my
training app.
And keep in mind, the other people
that do what I do for business,
like teaching
people how to make more money,
they never really had profitable fitness
businesses.
Then the books. Books are hard to sell.
My royalty's like a pound a book.
Got the accolade three times,
"Sunday Times" number one best-selling
author.
Not just best-selling author.
There's people out there telling you
they're a
best-selling author. They came ninth,
mate.
They came ninth in "The Sunday Times"
chart, and they're showing off about it.
I wouldn't. Then this business,
I do the exact same method right
there. And Noonic. You ever notice
that we run some promotions where we
literally
don't even make our money back?
So why would a business sell a bundle at a
loss?
So we can get your email address.
Because considering 55% of orders order
again,
the people that don't order again,
we can just email,
and we can email them other
products. "Hey,
do you want to try creatine?
Hey,
do you want to try Focus Blend?" Whatever
it is.
The email is the missing link in so many
of your kind of funnels.
And the crazy thing here is
if you now start selling less on social
media, you
can start to make more sales. Crazy.
Now, nothing that I've told you today
is really going to make sense
if you haven't
already established a very powerful
personal brand.
So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to link you to a video here.
Just start watching it now.
Just get comfortable.
Just watch the first 10 minutes,
because when you learn how to build a
personal
brand,
all of this becomes 10 times easier.
Thanks for watching.